# SOHAM DUTTA

# Front-End / Web Developer

#### CONTACT

xzoham@gmail.com

(917)-855-9843

Brooklyn, NY 👂

https://www.linkedin.com/in/soham-dut

a-ny "

sohamdutta.com

#### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Academy Bootcamp 553 hours of full-stack web development coursework March 2020 - June 2020 New York, NY

> Long Island University Biology / Pre-Pharmacy June 2016 - June 2019 Brooklyn, NY

> > **Awards**

**Honors Society** 

#### **SKILLS**

#### Languages

JavaScript Typescript HTML5 CSS / SCSS / SASS GraphQL

#### Libraries

React.js GatsbyJS Redux jQuery

> Axios Node.js

#### **PROFILE**

I am a Front-End / Web Developer with 3+ years of industry experience working for FieldRoutes and ServiceTitan, as well as freelancing with clients directly to develop their dream websites. Passionate about aesthetics and blending the art of design with programming. Experienced in working with a team to design, develop, test, and deliver pixel perfect and responsive web applications on a deadline. I enjoy solving problems and finding new ways to optimize performance.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Front End Developer

ServiceTitan

February 2022 - November 2023 / Remote

- Migrated existing CMS from Kentico to Strapi whilst optimizing and updating all components within our software.
- Perform debugging and troubleshooting of applications using JIRA.
- Write detailed technical documentation outlining system architecture, coding conventions and best practices.
- Implement agile development practices across multiple projects, ensuring timely delivery of high-quality solutions.
- Implement software components to automate manual processes.
- Develop pixel perfect components using Javascript, SCSS, and HTML, on the React framework, based off of Adobe XD designs.

## Front End Developer

FieldRoutes

May 2021 - February 2022 / Remote

- Transferred over legacy code base to a modern framework using React, Gatsby, and Kentico as one of the first developers on the team with React and Javascript experience.
- Developed a scalable templating software for our clients to quickly deploy fully customizable websites.
- Executed software build and release processes.
- Wrote technical documentation for users and colleagues regarding system architecture and development process.
- Researched and implemented emerging technologies and best practices in software engineering.
- Analyzed user needs to determine necessary improvements to existing software.
- Participated in Agile sprint planning meetings to discuss development tasks.
- Debugged issues in existing codebase to identify root cause of problems.
- $\bullet \quad \text{Integrated third-party API's into existing applications for additional functionality}.\\$

#### Frameworks

React.js GatsbyJS jQuery JestJS

Context API React Hooks

#### Additional Technologies Used

Adobe XD
Headless CMS (Kentico & Strapi)
Gatsby Cloud
Jira
MongoDB
PostgreSQL

# Full-Stack Developer

Freelance Web Development

September 2020 - May 2021 / Brooklyn, NY

- Designed and developed web pages for local small businesses and clients.
- Used React, Javascript, Typescript, SCSS, GraphQL, Headless CMS, and Netlify to manage the creation and deployment of sites.
- Worked directly with clients in the process of UI/UX design.
- Created efficient and scaleable website architecture.
- Created scaleable CMS architecture and efficient queries as well as trained clients on how to implement changes using a CMS.
- Met client deadlines and offered support and maintenance of all sites built.
- Developed pixel perfect and responsive websites.
- Used various API's to meet client needs.